Guide to the Robert Flaherty Film Seminar Archive 1949 - 2011 MSS.326
Fales Library and Special Collections
Robert Flaherty Film Seminar Archive
1949-2011
1958-2011
Fales Library and Special Collections
Flaherty International Film Seminar
MSS.326
105.5 Linear Feet (70 boxes + roll storage)
The Flaherty Seminar, named in honor of filmmaker Robert Flaherty (1884-1951), is an annual film event for filmmakers, critics, curators, musicians, and film enthusiasts founded by his widow and filmmaking partner Frances in 1955. The Robert Flaherty Film Seminar Archives contains over 1,200 video and audio recordings of activities and discussions that occurred at the various Seminars in their over fifty-year history.
Arrangement
The archivist rearranged the order of the video and audio recordings as donated by The Flaherty into five thematically-organized series.
The paper materials are organized into two series and are arranged chronologically by year, and alphabetically within the years. This material is described at the box level.
Historical Note
The Robert Flaherty Film Seminar is the longest continuously running film event in North America. Named after director Robert Flaherty, The Seminar began in 1955 when Flaherty's widow, Frances, convened a group of filmmakers, critics, curators, musicians, and other film enthusiasts at the Flaherty farm in Vermont. For more than fifty years the Flaherty Seminar has been firmly established as a one-of-a-kind institution that seeks to encourage filmmakers and other artists to explore the potential of the moving image. The films of such directors as Robert Drew, Louis Malle, the Maysles brothers, Mira Nair, Satyajit Ray, John Cassavetes, Yasujiro Ozu, Pedro Costa and Robert M. Young were shown at the Seminar before they were known generally in the American film community.
The weeklong Seminar brings together over 160 filmmakers, artists, curators, scholars, students, and film enthusiasts to celebrate the power of the moving image. Registration is open to the public and participants gather for a communal living experience that includes meals, social hours, special events, and at least three screening sessions daily followed by discussion. A different programmer is selected each year to shape the Seminar's theme and objective, which relates to a regional or national cinema, examines a stylistic feature, or responds to current world events. The Seminar is an intimate and intense experience where the traditional barriers between maker and audience are gradually obliterated. The structure of the event ensures that participants have greater access to the featured artists than would be found at festivals or conferences.
Source:
The Flaherty
Biographical Note
Robert Flaherty (1884-1951) was an American filmmaker who created the documentary films Nanook of the North (1922), Moana (1926), Man of Aran (1934), and Louisiana Story (1948). He is credited with originating the docufiction and ethnofiction film genres. The Flaherty Seminar, named in his honor, is an annual film event established by his widow and filmmaking partner Frances at the Flaherty farm in Vermont in 1955. Each weeklong Seminar held since then brings together filmmakers, artists, curators, scholars, students, and film enthusiasts for special events, social hours, and daily film screenings followed by discussions. A different programmer is selected each year to shape the Seminar's theme and objective. In its over fifty-year history the Flaherty Seminar, which now meets in upstate New York, has encouraged filmmakers to celebrate the legacy of Robert Flaherty's filmmaking and to explore the potential of the moving image. Sources: About the Flaherty Seminar The Flaherty Donates the Robert Flaherty Film Seminar Audio Collection to NYU Fales Library and Special Collections
Scope and Content
The Robert Flaherty Film Seminar Archive includes over 1,200 recordings dating back to the 1958 Flaherty Seminar. The recordings, of film screenings and discussions at the yearly Seminars, feature insight from Charles Burnett, Shirley Clarke, Bruce Connor, Frances Flaherty, Hollis Frampton, William Greaves, Ken Jacobs, Pauline Kael, Barbara Kopple, Richard Leacock, David Maysles, and Agnes Varda.
In addition to the Flaherty Seminar video and audio recordings, the collection also contains all paper records and photographs from The Flaherty organization.
The collection comprises seven series:
Series I: Flaherty Film Seminars.
This series contains audio and video recordings of the Flaherty Film Seminars ranging from 1958 to 2011.
Series II: Public TV.
This series contains audio recordings from annual meetings held at Arden House NY, during which independent producers met with public TV program managers and executives to screen and discuss controversial material.
Series III: Flaherty Israel.
This series contains audio recordings from the 1998 Flaherty Film Seminar in Israel, organized in collaboration with the New Foundation for Cinema and Television, Tel Aviv.
Series IV: Film Council.
This series contains audio recordings from a 1974 meeting of the Film Council, a group of non profit film exhibition folks: librarians, museums and distributors in NYC, who met once a month to talk about non commercial film.
Series V: Flaherty + Misc.
This series contains miscellaneous of audio material from various Film Seminars and activities.
Series VI: Seminar and Administrative Papers.
This series contains the paper records of the Robert Flaherty Film Seminar Archive. It consists of packets and brochures handed out at the seminars, programs, press and publicity, planning, grant applications, and all papers pertaining to the daily operations of the organization. The papers have been arranged chronologically by year, and alphabetically within the year. Original folder titles have been maintained where possible.
Series VII: Financial Papers.
This series contains the financial papers of the Robert Flaherty Film Seminar Archive. It includes budget reports, tax papers, cancelled checks, bills, and all other financial material. The papers have been arranged chronologically by year, and alphabetically within the year. Original folder titles have been maintained where possible.
Conditions Governing Access
Repository permission is required for access. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Provenance
The Robert Flaherty Film Seminar Archives was donated to Fales Library by Mary Kerr, Executive Director of The Flaherty, in 2012.
Provenance
The Robert Flaherty Film Seminar Archive was donated to NYU Libraries in 2012.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Access to audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact special.collections@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Audiovisual materials.; Flaherty, Robert J. (Robert Joseph), 1884-1951; Flaherty, Frances Hubbard
- Series I: Flaherty Film Seminars, 253680
  Scope and Content
  This series contains audio and video recordings of the Flaherty Film Seminars ranging from 1958 to 2011.
  - Subseries A: Audio Recordings, 253681
    - 4th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 1, August 19, 1958; ID: 326.0003; 253689 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0003, Case 326.0003_pt.1, Case 326.0003_pt.2)
      Existence and Location of Copies
      Access CD available. Please request parts 1 and 2.
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
      Duration: 119 minutes
      Original Format: 1/4" audio reel
      Original Number: 1958-01
      Opening: Hugh Gray, Frances Flaherty, FHF: "Nanook" Introduction, Robert Gardner.
    - 4th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 2, 1958; ID: 326.0004; 253690 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0004, Case 326.0004_pt.1, Case 326.0004_pt.2)
      Existence and Location of Originals
      Duration: 125 minutes
      Original Number: 1958-02
      John Marshall, Robert Gardner, Morris R. Mitchell, Jack Churchill, Robert Hughes.
      Conditions Governing Access
      Available.
    - 4th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 3, 1958; ID: 326.0005; 253695 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0005, Case 326.0005_pt.1, Case 326.0005_pt.2)
      Duration: 100 minutes
      Original Number: 1958-03
      Robert Hughes, David Riesman.
    - 4th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 4, 1958; ID: 326.0006; 253698 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0006, Case 326.0006_pt.1, Case 326.0006_pt.2)
      Original Number: 1958-04
      David Riesman, Rickie Leacock, George Stoney.
    - 4th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 5, 1958; ID: 326.0007; 253699 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0007, Case 326.0007)
      Duration 73 minutes
      Original Number: 1958-05
      George Stoney, Ike Kleinman.
      Access CD available.
    - 4th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 6, 1958; ID: 326.0008; 253703 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0008, Case 326.0008_pt.1, Case 326.0008_pt.2)
      Duration: 124 minutes
      Original Number: 1958-06
      Ike Kleinesman, Lou Applebaum.
    - 4th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 7, 1958; ID: 326.0009; 253705 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0009, Case 326.0009_pt.1, Case 326.0009_pt.2)
      Duration: 137 minutes
      Original Number: 1958-07
      Lou Applebaum, Satayajit Ray.
    - 4th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 8, 1958; ID: 326.0010; 253706 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0010, Case 326.0010_pt.1, Case 326.0010_pt.2)
      Duration: 133 minutes
      Original Number: 1958-08
      Ed Harrison, Satyajit Ray.
    - 4th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 9, August 21, 1958; ID: 326.0011; 253708 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0011, Case 326.0011)
      Duration: 17 minutes
      Original Number: 1958-09
      Morris R. Mitchell: The Film in Education, Introducing Films from Puerto Rico.
    - 4th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 9, August 28, 1958; ID: 326.0012; 253709 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0012, Case 326.0012)
      Duration: 24 minutes
      Satyajit Ray - "The Unvanquished" Seminar Conclusion, Hugh Gray - "The Conversazione".
    - 4th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 10, 1958; ID: 326.0013; 253713 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0013, Case 326.0013)
      Duration: 41 minutes
      Original Number: 1958-10
      [Unclear what Presto means. Probably is the end of R. Dyer Bennet speech]
    - 4th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 11, August 27, 1958; ID: 326.0014; 253714 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0014, Case 326.0014)
      Duration: 30 minutes
      Original Number: 1958-011
      Last part Dyer Bennet. Henry Martin: "Lincolnshire Poacher", "Buckeye Jim", "Joseph + Mary", "Roving Gambler".
    - 9th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 1, August 25, 1963; ID: 326.0015; 253715 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0015, Case 326.0015)
      Duration: 55 minutes
      Original Number: 1963-01
      Pierre Perrault, "Pour La Suite Du Monde".
    - 9th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 2, August 25, 1963; ID: 326.0016; 253716 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0016, Case 326.0016)
      Duration: 66 minutes
      Original Number: 1963-02
      "The Chair" introduction by Ricky Leacock, "Petey & Johnny" and general discussion. Tape 1.
    - 9th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 3, August 26, 1963; ID: 326.0017; 253718 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0017, Case 326.0017)
      Duration: 61 minutes
      Original Number: 1963-03
      Dick Leacock, etc. Tape II: Introduction to "Lousiana Story" by Virgil Thompson.
    - 9th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 4, 1963; ID: 326.0018; 253720 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0018, Case 326.0018)
      Duration: 68 minutes
      Original Number: 1963-04
      Discussion of "Louisiana Story" [A.M.] and introduction to "Nanook" and "Moana", Mrs. Flaherty.
    - 9th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 5, 1963; ID: 326.0019; 253721 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0019, Case 326.0019)
      Duration: 51 minutes
      Original Number: 1963-05
      Introduction to: "Olive Tree of Justice" by Louis Marcorelles, Introduction to: "Louisiana Study" film by George A and Mrs.Flaherty, Introduction to: Asian Films.
    - 9th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 6, 1963; ID: 326.0020; 253722 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0020, Case 326.0020)
      Original Number: 1963-06
      Discussion and introduction to Asian Films by: Ted Conant, Introduction: "The Pick-Pocket" by Colin Young, and discussion.
    - 9th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 7, August 27, 1963; ID: 326.0021; 253725 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0021, Case 326.0021)
      Duration: 59 minutes
      Original Number: 1963-07
      Discussion of "The Pick-Pocket".
    - 9th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 8, August 29, 1963; ID: 326.0022; 253735 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0022, Case 326.0022)
      Duration: 65 minutes
      Original Number: 1963-08
      Discussion on film in general, Talk by Iris Barry, Introduction by Erik Barnouw and F Flaherty.
    - 9th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 9, August 28, 1963; ID: 326.0023; 253744 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0023, Case 326.0023)
      Duration: 67 minutes
      Original Number: 1963-09
      Discussion on Film - Iris Barry leading, Intro: Dead Birds, Robert Gardner, Some bad interference for short period in R. Gardner lako.
    - 9th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 10, August 28, 1963; ID: 326.0024; 253745 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0024, Case 326.0024)
      Original Number: 1963-10
      The Birds - Robert Gardner, Discussion.
    - 9th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 11, August 26, 1963; ID: 326.0025; 253746 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0025, Case 326.0025)
      Original Number: 1963-11
      The Birds - R. Gardner, Discussion. [Cronloue de un ele intro].
    - 9th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 12, August 28, 1963; ID: 326.0026; 253747 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0026, Case 326.0026)
      Duration: 60 minutes
      Original Number: 1963-12
      Chronicle in the summer discussion.
    - 9th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 13, August 29, 1963; ID: 326.0027; 253748 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0027, Case 326.0027)
      Duration: 64 minutes
      Original Number: 1963-13
      Intro: Men of [Aran], Discussion [and] Mrs. Flaherty.
    - 9th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 14, August 29, 1963; ID: 326.0028; 253749 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0028, Case 326.0028)
      Duration: 62 minutes
      Original Number: 1963-14
      Discussion: Men of [Aran] and Mrs. Flaherty, Steve Ocko, USIA.
    - 9th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 15, August 29, 1963; ID: 326.0029; 253750 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0029, Case 326.0029_pt.1, Case 326.0029_pt.2)
      Duration: 95 minutes
      Original Number: 1963-15
      Steve Ocko - USIA, Intro: "The Walk" and "Bandits of Orgosolo", Discussion - "The Walk" and "The Magician", Screwed up tape - ran 3rd time - it's very late.
    - 9th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 16, August 30, 1963; ID: 326.0030; 253751 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0030, Case 326.0030_pt.1, Case 326.0030_pt.2)
      Duration: 96 minutes
      Original Number: 1963-16
      Canadian Film Board films study film, and Mrs. Flaherty on "LA Story".
    - 9th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 17, August 30, 1963; ID: 326.0031; 253752 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0031, Case 326.0031_pt.1, Case 326.0031_pt.2)
      Duration: 97 minutes
      Original Number: 1963-17
      Evelyn Wood lecture and discussion.
    - 9th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 18, August 31, 1963; ID: 326.0032; 253753 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0032, Case 326.0032_pt.1, Case 326.0032_pt.2)
      Original Number: 1963-18
      Evelyn Wood continued, Maysles (Showman), Discussion: "Showman".
    - 9th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 19, August 31, 1963; ID: 326.0033; 253754 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0033, Case 326.0033_pt.1, Case 326.0033_pt.2)
      Duration: 90 minutes
      Original Number: 1963-19
      Maysles - little, Intro to "Semaine de la Mauvaise etc" by Jean [Aerman] good discussion! Discussion of "The City", Intro - study film 6, Discussion and J.Cohen's.
    - 9th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 20, August 31, 1963; ID: 326.0034; 253755 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0034, Case 326.0034)
      Original Number: 1963-20
      Discussion: "The Music Room".
    - 9th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 21, 1963; ID: 326.0035; 253756 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0035, Case 326.0035)
      Original Number: 1963-21
      "A Tout Prendre" discussion.
    - 9th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 22, September 1, 1963; ID: 326.0036; 253757 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0036, Case 326.0036)
      Original Number: 1963-22
      Continue, "The House Holden", Intro: "Un Coeur Gros Comme Ca," "Cuba si!" Final evaluation.
    - 10th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 1, August 31, 1964; ID: 326.0037; 253758 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0037, Case 326.0037)
      Duration: 77 minutes
      Original Number: 1964-01
      Side 1: 000 to 015 blank, 015 to 880 Introduction by Mrs. Frances Flaherty, 080 to 141 Introduction of "The Monsters of the [Sesuicu] by Colin Young, 141 to 268 Introduction to the film "Processional" and minor international points about future films.
      Film: "The Processional" (Nation Film Board of... 270 to 279 Nothing.
      Film: The Beatles, Maysles. called "What's Happening?" (with the Beatles), 279- to end discussions with David Maysles about the Bettles film.
      Side 2: 000-015 blank, 015-020 at 71/2 rest 3 3/4, 015 to 145 cont. of side 1 with Maysles, 145 to 841 Introduction to afternoon program by Colin Young wiht Maysles, Cont. of discussion of making film like the "Beatles".
    - 10th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 2, August 1, 1964; ID: 326.0038; 253759 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0038, Case 326.0038)
      Duration: 58 minutes
      Original Number: 1964-02
      Reel 2. Side 1: continuation of program with David Maysles and Colin Young: "Made in the U.S.A." [Kino], "Zoo" (Dutch), "Santero (P.R. Film), "Ed and Frank" (Mitchel), "My Childhood" [ metvo], Talk about "Ed and Frank".
      Side 2: continuation of discussion of "Ed and Frank" with Colin Young: Film: "Tokyo Story", Introduction of the morning program, "Central Market", Discussion with Mel Sloan, [Ediyou] about "Central Market", "The Bus".
    - 10th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 3, 1964; ID: 326.0039; 253760 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0039, Case 326.0039_pt.1, Case 326.0039_pt.2)
      Duration: 115 minutes
      Original Number: 1964-03
      Side 1: "The March" (U.S.I.A.), "The Bus".
      Side 2: Discussion of the film: "Faces of November: Discussion: "That's Where I Am At", Discussion: "The Streets of Greenwood".
    - 10th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 4, 1964; ID: 326.0040; 253761 (Box 1, Media ID: 326.0040, Case 326.0040_pt.1, Case 326.0040_pt.2)
      Duration: 129 minutes
      Original Number: 1964-04
      Side 1: Continuation of "The Streets of Greenwood", Discussion of "Grassroots", "My Childhood".
      Side 2: Discussion "Tokyo Story", Introduction to "Nanook" by Mrs. Frances Flaherty.
    - 10th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 5, 1964; ID: 326.0041; 253762 (Box 2, Media ID: 326.0041, Case 326.0041_pt.1, Case 326.0041_pt.2)
      Side 1: [Clark], Talk by Mrs. Frances Flaherty on Nanook, George Stoney, "How to Look at a City", "The City".
      Side 2: George Stoney on films and outtakes of "Churches in the Hills", [Mr. Yang], James Beveridge.
      Original Format: audio cassette
      Original Number: 1964-05
    - 10th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 6, 1964; ID: 326.0042; 253763 (Box 2, Media ID: 326.0042, Case 326.0042_pt.1, Case 326.0042_pt.2)
      Duration: 107 minutes
      Original Number: 1964-06
      Side 1: James Beveridge. Side 2: Mel Sloan on USC, Peter Brooks.
    - 10th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 7, 1964; ID: 326.0043; 253764 (Box 2, Media ID: 326.0043, Case 326.0043)
      Original Number: 1964-07
      Side 1: film on Hartford and following discussion.
    - 10th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 8, 1964; ID: 326.0044; 253765 (Box 2, Media ID: 326.0044, Case 326.0044_pt.1, Case 326.0044_pt.2)
      Duration: 102 minutes
      Original Number: 1964-08
      Mr. Leacock. Sound [ ] of ABC film made up from.
      Maysles film "Showman". Discussion on the tape by [Thorold] Dickinson.
    - 11th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 1, 1964; ID: 326.0045; 253766 (Box 2, Media ID: 326.0045, Case 326.0045)
      Original Number: 1965-01
      Beveridge, Comment on "Cindy Fink" by Beveridge, Introduction for R. Guenette by Beveridge, Talk by R. Guenette on William Faulkner's "On Mississippi", Comment by Low on campfire sequence and crew and procedure.
      Intro by Erik Barnouw-who does what + who is who, Intro of Lillian Ross by J. Beveridge, Lillian Ross introducs "Dancers in May", Comment by J. Beveridge analysis of film, Lillian Ross describes the making of the film.
    - 11th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 2, 1965; ID: 326.0046; 253767 (Box 2, Media ID: 326.0046, Case 326.0046)
      Original Number: 1965-02
      Lillian Ross "Dancers in May", Intro to Selma Films by J.B, Comment on Selma Films by J.B, INtro to Emchwiller by J.B, common by Emschwiller on opportunity and work.
    - 11th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 3, 1965; ID: 326.0047; 253768 (Box 2, Media ID: 326.0047, Case 326.0047)
      Duration: 63 minutes
      Original Number: 1965-03
      Continuation of Emschwiller, Comment on "The Berkeley Rebels" by Arthur Barron.
    - 11th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 4, 1965; ID: 326.0048; 253769 (Box 2, Media ID: 326.0048, Case 326.0048)
      Original Number: 1965-04
      Arthur Barron (cont), Intro to Pearson J.B. Comment on Pearson J.B.
      Dennis King- film on V.D. "The Silent Epidemic", Intro to "Raga" and "Meet Marlon Brando", Discussion.
    - 11th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 5, 1965; ID: 326.0049; 253770 (Box 2, Media ID: 326.0049, Case 326.0049)
      Original Number: 1965-05
      "Brando" (continued), "Bethune", "Sunday".
      Intro to Dutch films by Sluizer, "Sunday" and "Sea", "Colossus and Fighter", Manfred Kirchheimer.
    - 11th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 6, 1965; ID: 326.0050; 253771 (Box 2, Media ID: 326.0050, Case 326.0050)
      Duration: 42 minutes
      Original Number: 1965-06
      "The Young Fighter", "Colossus on the River", Cinema Verite, Claire-Obscur, Intro to [Allemph] "Lord's Land".
    - 11th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 7, 1965; ID: 326.0051; 253772 (Box 2, Media ID: 326.0051, Case 326.0051)
      Original Number: 1965-07
      "Lord's Land", "Fishing on the Coast of Japan" and "Israel: The Julien Bryan Story of the Jewish People."
      Stan Vanderbeek- intro an dcomment on his films, George Stoney "The Mask," "Under Pressure".
    - 11th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 8, 1965; ID: 326.0052; 253773 (Box 2, Media ID: 326.0052, Case 326.0052)
      Duration: 50 minutes
      Original Number: 1965-08
      George Stoney (continued).
    - 11th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 9, 1965; ID: 326.0053; 253774 (Box 2, Media ID: 326.0053, Case 326.0053)
      Original Number: 1965-09
      George Stoney (continued), Introduction to "A Valparaiso" by Ivens, Talk on "Americans from Jungaria", Intro to "Antonio Gaudi" and "Time Is", "The Winner".
    - 11th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 10, 1965; ID: 326.0054; 253775 (Box 2, Media ID: 326.0054, Case 326.0054)
      Original Number: 1965-10
      "The Winner", "Happy Birthday, Lenny", 3 U.S.C. films, "Dylan Thomas" by Rollie McKenna, "The Squeeze" by Hillary Harris, Dance film.
    - 11th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 11, 1965; ID: 326.0055; 253776 (Box 2, Media ID: 326.0055, Case 326.0055)
      Original Number: 1965-11
      Harris, "Filgate", "Fruite of Fear", George Stevens, Jr.
    - 11th Annual Flaherty Seminar - Tape 12, 1965; ID: 326.0056; 253777 (Box 2, Media ID: 326.0056, Case 326.0056)
      Original Number: 1965-12